allianzlife.com 2010-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Allianz Life Insurance Company of North America

|   
---|---  
| 

At Allianz Life Insurance Company of North America, protecting your privacy is very important to us. This Privacy Policy applies to all of the companies within the Allianz family listed below. Our policy is to treat the personal information you furnish us with the utmost respect and in accordance with applicable privacy laws and regulations. Please read on for details about our practices for handling and securing your personal information. 

This Privacy Policy is currently applicable only to our United States customers and visitors when they interact with our web site. 

**Anonymous browsing**  
You can visit us on the internet without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself, including your email address. 

Our web servers only collect the name of the domain you used to access the internet (such as aol.com) and the web site you came from and visit next through a cookie. Cookies are small pieces of data stored by your internet browser on your computer's hard drive. A cookie, by itself, does not reveal to us your email address or who you are. It cannot be used to collect data from your hard drive, or obtain your email address or personal-identifying information about you. The information we collect is used by us and our business partners to measure the number of visits, average time spent, page views, and other general statistics about visitors to our web site in general. We also use this data to monitor site performance and to make the site easier and more convenient to use. 

If you decide to register online with one of our business units, we may collect additional information to provide tailored offerings or content to you. In this case, we use cookies to recognize you on subsequent visits and make your online experience more convenient. 

You may set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to prevent cookies from being sent. Please note, however, that by not accepting cookies, you will limit the functionality we can provide you when you visit our site. 

**Personal information collection**  
If you decide to register online with one of our business units, your browsing will no longer be anonymous to us. We may ask you for information about yourself to assist us in meeting your various needs, including:

  * Providing you with products or services you have requested 
  * Servicing your account 
  * Improving our services 
  * Informing you of additional products or services that may be of interest 

To provide these products and services, we may need to ask you directly to provide, among other things, your name, social security number, physical address, zip code, email address and phone number. 

Please note that we do not knowingly solicit information from children and we do not knowingly market our products or services to children. 

**Sharing information and consumer choice**  
When you provide information to us, it is not shared with any third party, unless requested by you or permitted by law. We may share your information with our affiliated companies and third parties for the purpose of fulfilling your requests and servicing your Allianz products. We may also collect and summarize statistics that we gather about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, and services and provide these statistics to third parties; however, when we do, these statistics will not include any personal information that identifies individuals. 

**Securing and protecting your information**  
We use encryption and authentication tools to protect your personal information. Information you provide us through our web site is secure. 

We instruct our employees with access to your information that it is to be used only in accordance with the principles set forth in this Privacy Policy and the privacy laws and regulations applicable to each of our specific business units. Employees who misuse customer information are subject to disciplinary action up to and including termination of employment. 

**To contact us or correct your information**  
If you wish to access, remove or correct any personally identifying data you have supplied to us, or if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, you may reach us by mail, phone, or email by clicking on the “Contact Us” link at the top of this page. 

If you believe that an error has been made in the accuracy of the data collected from you, we will correct such error upon adequate verification of the error and the identity of the person seeking the correction. Please understand that in order to protect your privacy and security, we may also need to take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. 

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**  
We reserve the right to modify or supplement this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make any material change to our practices, we will update our Privacy Policy to include such changes.

**Allianz family of companies**

  * Allianz Life Insurance Company of North America
  * Allianz Financial Services, LLC
  * Allianz Life and Annuity Company

**Date of last revision:** 7/12/2010
